Who am I?
（赤司(あかし)）僕は誰だ
僕は誰だ
I...
僕は…
I am...
You are my weakness.
（赤司）オマエはオレの弱さだ
I was trying to save it by winning.
（赤司）オレは勝つことで
つなぎとめようとした
Something irreplaceable.
かけがえのないものを
Our guilt will stay with us forever.
オレたちの罪は
決して消えはしないだろう
I thought it couldn't hurt to lose.
敗北するなら
それもいいと思っていた
But it seems I was wrong.
だが…
やはりそうはいかないようだ
How dare you ask who I am?
（赤司）誰とは心外だな
It Was You
（根武谷(ねぶや)）
出してくれって 赤司
You want to play?
Akashi, you could barely play a second ago!
さっきまで
ヨレヨレだったじゃねえか！
大丈夫なんだろうな？
You're sure you okay?
Yes. I disgraced myself.
見苦しい姿を見せた
I feel badly about it.
それについては悪いと思っている
I'm sorry.
すまない
（白金(しろがね)）あ…
（葉山(はやま)）ええ…!?
What?
（実渕(みぶち)）うそ…
征(せい)ちゃんが謝った…!?
No way. Sei-chan apologized?
もう一度力を貸してほしい
I want you to lend me your strength
again so we can beat Seirin.
誠凛(せいりん)に勝つために
Rakuzan
Seirin
Defense! Defense! Defense!
（誠凛部員たち）ディーフェンス！
ディーフェンス！
Let's stop them! No matter what!
（日向(ひゅうが)）止めんぞ 絶対！
Yeah!
（伊月(いづき)･木吉(きよし)）おお！
Let's go, Kagami-kun.
（黒子(くろこ)）行きましょう 火神(かがみ)君
Yeah.
What is this? Akashi's changed in some way.
（火神）なんだ…？
今までの赤司と何か違う…！
来る！ 集中しろ！
He's coming. Focus.
I can't beat Akashi unless
I focus completely.
全神経を注がなきゃ
赤司は倒せねえ！
ふっ… 久しぶりだね
It's been a while,
黒子
Kuroko.
What?
美しいシュートだ
That was a beautiful shot.
Well done, Mibuchi.
いいぞ 実渕
No way. Sei-chan cheered me on?
（実渕）うっそ…
征ちゃんがエール…!?
それに今のパス
And the position, timing,
and angle of the ball's seams
位置 タイミング—
指にかかるボールの
縫い目の角度まで完璧
against my fingers
were perfect just now.
I've never taken such a comfortable
shot during a game before.
試合中にあんなに気持ちよく
シュート打てたのなんて初めてだわ
What's going on?
なんなのよ もうっ
This is getting exciting.
テンション上がっちゃうわね
（黄瀬(きせ)）うわ… なんか今のパスで
分かっちゃったっス
That pass told me everything.
Those are the passes we received.
（緑間(みどりま)）
オレたちがいつも受けてきたパス
Which means...
（紫原(むらさきばら)）てことは…
Akashi is back to his old self.
（青峰(あおみね)）昔の赤司に戻ってる…
なっ… マジかよ!?
What? Seriously?
Now that the true Akashi-kun's awake,
he's almost certainly stronger than before.
本来の赤司君が
目を覚ましたことで—
前より
はるかに手強くなったのは—
間違いありません
In other words, the real game starts now.
（火神）つまり
こっからが本番ってことかよ…
Bring it on!
上等だぜ！
（伊月）しまった！
なんてパスだ…
Crap! What a pass!
And this space...
しかもこのスペースは…
（葉山）オレの
一番得意な場所だよん
This place is my specialty!
This speed at this distance...
（木吉）このスピードで
この間合い… マズい
This is bad. It's Hayama in his best form.
完全に葉山の形だ！
（木吉）う… ぐ… ええい
Yeah!
おっしゃー
All right!
Akashi-kun's changed since the timeout.
（リコ）タイムアウト明けの
赤司君の豹変…
Rakuzan has regained their composure,
but we're scoring, too.
洛山(らくざん)は調子を
取り戻したみたいだけど—
ウチも点は取れてる
けど… 胸騒ぎがする
But I feel uneasy.
Why do I feel like something's wrong?
この違和感は何…？
（火神）おかしい…
どういうことだ？
That's odd. What's going on?
He's amazing,
確かにすげえけど—
but the other members of the Generation
of Miracles were far more threatening.
これだけの選手なら—
他の“キセキの世代”のほうが
ずっと脅威を感じる
Did I imagine that chill earlier?
さっきの寒気は
気のせいだったのか？
（若松(わかまつ)）けど 赤司は思ったより…
普通じゃないスか？
Doesn't Akashi seem surprisingly normal?
Normal? Yeah, right.
（今吉(いまよし)）普通？ まさか
同業者からしたら
化けもんにしか見えへんで
As a point guard myself,
he looks like a monster to me.
High speed passes from still position.
（高尾(たかお)）
ノーモーションからの高速パス…
The ability to dribble
without looking at his hands.
手元をまったく見ない
ドリブルスキルと—
完璧に把握されたコートビジョン…
Total vision of the court.
（笠松(かさまつ)）一見 赤司が
アシストして決めてるようだが—
At first glance it looks like Akashi's
making assists, but that's not all.
それだけじゃない…
As Akashi's teammates receive his
passes, their movements improve.
赤司のパスを受けた
選手の動きが—
どんどん よくなってる
（緑間）完璧なパスは
完璧なリズムを作る
Perfect passes create perfect rhythm.
赤司はエンペラーアイで
敵味方すべてを把握し—
Akashi's Emperor Eye sees
opponents and allies alike.
およそ狙って出すのは
不可能なパスを自在に操り—
He easily makes what should
be impossible passes,
drawing out the full
potential of his teammates.
味方の潜在能力を限界まで
引き出している
（伊月）うっ… は！
（日向）ゾーン…！
The Zone...
We're just getting started.
いや… こっからか
Relax. This game won't turn
out the way you fear it will.
そう身構えるな
心配しなくても—
オマエの考えてるようなことには
ならないよ
（赤司）ゾーンと言っても—
I've simply returned to a previous state.
少し前の状態に戻っただけだ
オレ自身はもう
大袈裟に変わったりしない
I won't change dramatically anymore.
ただし他の４人は別だが
However, the same can't be
said for the other four.
ありえない…
No way.
（火神）ゾーンが…
５人全員…!?
All five of them are in the Zone?
（土田(つちだ)）そんな… ゾーンは
“キセキの世代”や火神クラス…
No way.
The Zone is attainable by guys of the
Generation of Miracles and Kagami's class.
Only a few prodigies can enter it.
限られた天才しか
入れないはずじゃ…
That's not a complete Zone.
（リコ）あれは
完全なゾーンじゃないわ
Akashi-kun's drawn out their potential
to a level approaching the Zone.
赤司君の力によって—
みんな限りなくゾーンに近い能力を
引き出されてるだけ
It's only possible because
they're the Uncrowned Kings.
でも それができるのは
五将の彼らだからこそよ
What are we supposed to do?
（小金井(こがねい)）こんなの…
どうすりゃいいんだよ…
（花宮(はなみや)）フハッ…
どうにもならねえに決まってんだろ
There's nothing they can do.
オレでも誠凛がかわいそうになるね
I almost feel sorry for Seirin. It's tragic.
悲惨すぎてよ
（日向）このプレッシャー…
This pressure...
It's no use. I can't go for Barrier
Jumpers, much less normal shots.
ダメだ…
通常のシュートはおろか—
バリアジャンパーの
ステップにすら入れない…！
Izuki!
伊月！
Crap!
（日向）しまっ…！
This is bad! Run back!
（木吉）まずい… 戻れっ！
（伊月）ぐっ… このスピードは…
This speed...
うっ… 行かすかぁ！
You're not going anywhere!
（葉山）チッ…
ならこれでどうだ！
Then how about this?
Lightning Dribble Level 5!
ライトニングドリブル レベル５！
Damn it. He's better than the others.
んなろっ！
やっぱ こいつは別格か！
（黛(まゆずみ)）はあ!?
いいのかよ赤司 あそこで
What? Are you sure you want it there, Akashi?
Don't blame me if they steal the ball.
取られてもしんねーぞ…
ぬうっ…
If you say so, it must be all right.
（黛）まあ 今のオマエが
そう言うなら大丈夫なんだろ！
（小金井）なっ…
根武谷のアリウープ!?
An alley-oop with Nebuya?
まだだあ！
It's not over yet!
火神ー！
Kagami!
（赤司）いいや…
No.
もうそこは
オマエの場所ではないよ 火神
That's not your place anymore, Kagami.
I can't reach him!
届かねえ…!?
おおらっ！
No way.
そんなっ…
（日向）どうする…
いよいよやべえぜ…
What should we do? This is getting bad.
はっ… しかも
ついに来ちまった…！
And we've finally reached
火神の体力の限界が…！
the limits of Kagami's stamina.
I can't breathe.
（火神）息が苦しい…
My limbs feel alien and heavy.
手足が自分のもんじゃ
ないみたいに重い…
My mind is dull. I can't
properly assess the situation.
思考が鈍って
状況判断もままならない
This is bad. I'm nearly running on empty.
ちくしょうっ… やべえ…
いよいよスッカラカンだ
This is bad. He's out of the Zone.
（小金井）マズい…
ゾーンも切れた
Kagami's completely out of gas.
火神 完全にガス欠…
We can't win without Kagami-kun.
（リコ）火神君抜きでは
勝ち目はない…
タイムアウトももう使えない…
We can't use any more timeouts, either.
何か… 何か手はないの…!?
Isn't there anything we can do?
Damn it. It's not over yet!
（日向）くそっ… まだだ！
You're slowing down.
（実渕）キレが落ちてるわよ！
そんなの 打たせると
思ってんの!?
You think I'll let you take that shot?
（日向）ぐうう…
（根武谷）ぐうう…
（木吉）ぐっ… ダメだ…
ポジションがとれないっ！
It's no use. I can't get in position.
ああ… うぐっ…！
His knee is finally screaming.
（根武谷）ついに
膝が悲鳴上げたか…
But I'll show no mercy.
けど容赦はしねーぞ
勝負だかんよ！
This is a battle!
おおら！
Perfect. It's time to repay the favor!
ちょーどいいや！
やられた借り
返させてもらうよん！
Look, look, look.
（伊月）見ろ 見ろ 見ろ…！
Predict Hayama's movements.
読むんだ 葉山の動きを！
You don't have to stop him.
止められなくてもいい！
At least slow them down with a foul.
せめてファウルで流れを切る！
It'll give Kagami a few seconds of rest.
そうすれば仕切り直しと—
わずかでも火神を休ませる
時間ができるはず…
This is the pseudo Emperor Eye.
（葉山）これは…
疑似エンペラーアイ！
黒子！
Kuroko!
（審判）プッシング！ 黒11番！
Pushing, black No. 11!
うっ… 惜しい！
That was close.
No, wait. Isn't this bad?
いや… むしろこれは
マズいんじゃないのか…？
（黒子）ハア ハア ハア…
（リコ）火神君だけじゃない…
全員 限界が近い
Kagami-kun's not the only one.
Everyone's approaching their limit.
そのせいで
運動能力も落ちてきてる…
Their physical abilities are dropping.
それに引き換え 洛山は—
In contrast, Akashi-kun's
improving Rakuzan's performance.
赤司君の力でパフォーマンスと
調子は上がっている
あまりに差がありすぎる…
The difference is too great.
ダメだ… もはや万事休す…
ここまでか!?
It's no use.
It's over.
This is the end.
（黒子）ハア ハア ハア…
（荻原(おぎわら)）
頑張れ 黒子！ 諦めるな！
You can do it, Kuroko!
Don't give up!
（荻原）頑張れ 黒子！
Ogiwara-kun...
荻原君！
あいつが…!?
That's him?
That kid...
（赤司）彼は確か…
（さつき）
全中決勝で戦ったテツ君の…
That's Tetsu-kun's friend we
played at the national finals.
Ogiwara-kun...
（黒子）荻原君…
But I...
けど…
ボクは君に…
ほら もっちー！
オマエも応援しろって！
Come on, Mocchi.
Cheer for him.
O-Okay.
（持田(もちだ)）お おうっ
あっ そうだ！
Oh, right.
Sheesh. I can't watch this.
（青峰）ったく… 見てらんねーぜ
おらぁ テツ！ 火神！
Tetsu, Kagami!
You beat us!
テメエら
オレらに勝ったんだろーが！
If you don't beat Rakuzan, I'll kill you!
洛山ぐれー倒さねーと
ぶっ殺すぞ！
青峰…
Aomine...
Dai-chan?
（さつき）大(だい)ちゃん…
Just so you know, so will I!
言っとくけどウチもっスからねー！
Win, Seirin!
勝てぇ 誠凛！
Beat Akashi! Beat Rakuzan!
倒してこい！ 赤司を！ 洛山を！
You're not saying anything, Atsushi?
（氷室(ひむろ)）敦(あつし)はいいのかい？
（紫原）やるわけねーし…
I'd never do that.
Don't give up, Seirin!
（津川(つがわ)）諦めるな 誠凛！
Seirin! Seirin! Seirin!
It wouldn't be interesting otherwise.
そうこなくては面白くない
（火神）黒子…
（黒子）ん…
Kuroko.
Cheers really lift you up, don't they?
応援ってのは
しみじみ元気出るなあ
Yes.
はい
Do you have a secy?
ちょっといいすか
Rakuzan
Seirin
Seirin was discussing something
amongst themselves.
誠凛は集まって何か話してたが…
Is there something they
can do to stop Rakuzan?
今の洛山に対抗できる手段なんて
あるのか？
If there is, it's the Zone greater
than the Zone Dai-chan mentioned.
（さつき）あるとすれば—
大ちゃんが言ってた
ゾーンを超えたゾーン…
けど…
But...
Can he move those huge doors and
the man standing in front of them?
（青峰）開けられんのか…？
バカでけえ扉と
その前に立つ誰か…
At the very least,
I couldn't make them budge.
少なくともオレは
ビクともさせられなかった
（赤司）火神をオレにつけて
ややタイト気味のマンツーマン…
They're running a tight man-to-man
defense with Kagami on me.
Nothing has changed.
今までとまったく変わっていない
Kagami has recovered,
but not enough to reenter the Zone.
火神も息は吹き返したが
ゾーンに入るほど戻ってはいない
（実渕）他の４人も同様…
It's the same for the other four.
動けてはいても
決して速くなったりはしていないわ
They're moving, but they're
not faster than before.
But...
けど…
（黛）なんだ
この得体の知れない圧力は…!?
What is this mysterious pressure?
Not even their quick passes are enough
to make their defense crumble.
（高尾）あの速いパス回しでも
ディフェンスが崩れない…
It feels like they're matching
their movements to something else.
というか ５人の動きが
何かに合わせてることで—
乱れないって感じだ…
Sei-chan!
（実渕）征ちゃん！
What?
（土田）なっ…！
（笠松）うまい…！
That was good!
（葉山）えい… はっ… てあっ
（火神）でーああ！
Kagami?
（今吉）火神!?
When did he enter the Zone?
（若松）
しかも いつの間にゾーンに!?
I believe it.
（葉山）まさかとは言わねーよ
I had a bad feeling about this.
嫌な予感はあったんだ
You haven't surprised me!
予想外じゃねえんだよ！
Was he prepared for this?
備えてたんか…!?
A double clutch?
ダブルクラッチ…
ええいっ！
だあ…
（小金井）うおおー！
（土田）止めたあー！
They stopped him!
チイ…
What was that?
（赤司）なんだ 今のは…
We caught Seirin off guard,
but they all reacted immediately.
確実に虚をついた誠凛の反応は
全員とっさのものだった
Regardless, how are they able to
coordinate with Kagami's movements?
にもかかわらず なぜ…
火神の動きに合わせて
連係が取れる…!?
（青峰）なんだ そういうことかよ
（さつき）ん？
I see. I get it.
（青峰）そんなことだったのかよ…
So that's how it is.
大… ちゃん…？
Dai-chan?
They're matching Kagami.
（赤司）火神に合わせる…
Could it be that the true Zone is...
まさか—
本当のゾーンとは…！
（火神）そうさ…
オレだけで戦うんじゃない！
That's right. It's not fighting alone.
It's fighting as a team!
みんなと戦うんだ…！
No wonder it wouldn't open.
（青峰）開かねえわけだ
I'd already abandoned you.
なんせオレは
捨てちまったんだからよ
He wasn't a gatekeeper.
門番なんかじゃなかった
The man standing in front of the door...
扉の前に立ってたのは…
It was you, Tetsu.
オマエだったんじゃねーか…
テツ…
They're synchronizing their movements
with a second of eye contact.
（赤司）チームメイトと
一瞬のアイコンタクトのみで—
動きをシンクロさせ—
Super high-speed teamwork
matching Kagami's Zone speed.
火神のゾーンスピードに合わせた
超速連係
The Direct Drive Zone!
ダイレクトドライブゾーン！
（小金井）抜いたあ！
いけぇ火神ー！
He passed him!
Go, Kagami!
I can't keep up with
Kagami's speed if I think.
（木吉）火神のスピードに
合わせるには—
考えていたら間に合わない
Don't think. Trust your intuition.
考えるな…
直感に委ねるんだ！
We can do it.
できるはずだ！
信じろ オレたちの絆を！
Believe in our bonds.
（火神）うーうっ！
（歓声）
（小金井）やったー！
Yes!
What just happened?
（津川）なんだ今の…
速すぎて目が追いつかねえ…
It was too fast to keep up.
Team play at the Zone's speed?
ゾーンの速さの
チームプレーなんて…
How is the even possible?
まさかそんなことが…
This is the Zone greater than the
Zone that lies beyond that door.
（赤司）これがあの扉の先…—
ゾーンを超えたゾーン…
いや…
No, this is its true form.
むしろこれが
本来あるべきカタチ
The true Zone.
真のゾーンなのか！
チッ… やっぱ
勝てねーかもしんねーなー
Maybe I can't win by myself.
オレ１人じゃ…
うん そーだね… 大ちゃん
Yeah. I think you're right, Dai-chan.
まさしく一心同体…
すげえチームだな 誠凛
They're playing as one.
Seirin is an amazing team.
ああ… それに
見ててワクワクする
Yeah. Just watching them is exciting.
I'd like to trying playing
with them sometime.
いつかやってみてーなあ
あいつらと
Defense, let's stop them!
（日向）ディフェンス
絶対止めんぞ！
Yeah!
Focus. Don't miss the shift
in his center of gravity.
（日向）集中しろ！
重心の変化を見落とすな！
If we leave defeated now,
it'll all be for nothing!
ここで退場なんてしたら
全部パアだぞ！
Is that Heaven?
（小金井）あれは… “天”!?
Pass, Mibuchi!
パスだ 実渕！
It's a trap!
そこは罠だ！
チイッ… うっ！
（歓声）
（土田）うおお 止めたー！
They stopped them!
（小金井）やったぁ！ いけえー！
Yes! Go!
日向だ 黛！
Get Hyuga, Mayuzumi!
This is intense.
すげえつばぜり合いだ…
息つく暇もねえな
There's no room to breathe.
（緑間）だが押しているのは誠凛だ
But Seirin's winning.
Akashi is supporting his
team with Emperor Eye,
赤司がエンペラーアイで
サポートしているが—
but Seirin's coordination is slightly faster.
それでも 誠凛の連係速度が
わずかに上回っている
If Seirin blocks another one of Rakuzan's
attacks, they'll be able to score.
誠凛はもう一度 洛山の攻撃を
防ぐことができれば—
得点できる可能性は十分にある！
Rakuzan
Seirin
Then they'll be only three points behind.
そうなれば３点差…
射程圏内だ！
They could win.
If we can stop them,
victory will be in reach!
止めれば勝利が見える！
ふりしぼれ！
最後の一滴まで！
Dig deep! Give every last drop!
Defense! Defense! Defense!
ディーフェンス！
ふんっ
I will win.
（赤司）勝つのは—
オレだ！
You're far too inexperienced to beat Rakuzan.
洛山を討つなど 百年早い！
Preview
Kagami has entered the true Zone,
but Rakuzan's victory is still secure!
（赤司）火神が
真のゾーンに入ったところで—
洛山の勝利は揺るがない
（黒子）最後まで諦めません
みんなと一緒に全力で戦います
We won't give up until the end.
We'll fight together, as hard as we can.
Yeah. Let show them how we
play basketball, Kuroko!
（火神）ああ オレたちのバスケを
見せてやろうぜ！ 黒子！
Again and Again
Yes, Kagami-kun!
（黒子）はい！ 火神君！